<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coming Soon on Wayism - The Butterfly Path</title><link>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/</link><description>Recent content in Coming Soon on Wayism - The Butterfly Path</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/xhugo-complete-files-summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/xhugo-complete-files-summary/</guid><description>Hugo Files Status &amp;amp; Next Steps Completed Hugo Files (6 of 6) ✅ _index.md — Overview page with book description, core concepts, what&amp;rsquo;s included vs. requires purchase
✅ philosophy.md — Theoretical framework, ten-mind system, three energy domains
✅ key-concepts.md — Essential terminology, definitions, practical understanding
✅ benefits.md — Why practice, scientific basis, daily life integration
✅ quotes.md — Key excerpts with page numbers
✅ ai-summary.md — Complete conceptual framework for AI reference</description></item><item><title>Avalokane Meditation: AI Reference Guide</title><link>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/ai-summary-avalokane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/ai-summary-avalokane/</guid><description>AI Reference Guide: Avalokane Meditation Complete Conceptual Framework Avalokane (Sanskrit: ava + lok + ane = &amp;ldquo;the art of beholding from above&amp;rdquo;) is an ancient Wayist meditation practice that teaches mystical beholding through spirit-minds rather than ordinary thinking. This practice represents authentic spiritual education based on logical principles rather than mystical entertainment.
Core Philosophical Framework Wayist Cosmological Structure Three Energy Domains:
Material Domain — physical reality, sensory experience, scientific measurement Soul Domain — emotional, psychological, interpersonal energies Spiritual Domain — divine energies, spirit-mind awareness, connection to Sukhavati Ten-Mind System of Human Awareness:</description></item><item><title>Avalokane Meditation: Benefits &amp; Applications</title><link>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/benefits-avalokane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/benefits-avalokane/</guid><description>Benefits &amp;amp; Applications of Avalokane Practice Why Develop Mystical Beholding Capabilities Spiritual Development Benefits Enhanced Spiritual Awareness Avalokane develops your natural capacity to perceive spiritual energy patterns in ordinary experience. This isn&amp;rsquo;t about achieving special states, but about recognizing the sacred dimensions always present but usually overlooked.
Individual Spiritual Authority Through Divine Tara guidance, you develop confidence in your own spiritual discernment rather than dependency on external teachers or group validation.</description></item><item><title>Avalokane Meditation: Key Concepts</title><link>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/key-concepts-avalokane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/key-concepts-avalokane/</guid><description>Key Concepts in Avalokane Practice Essential Sanskrit Terminology Avalokane (avalokāne) Etymology: ava (from above) + lok (to see/behold) + ane (the art of)
Definition: The practice of mystical beholding from a divine perspective
Application: Engaging spirit-minds to perceive reality beyond ordinary awareness
Upaya (upāya) Etymology: upa (near) + aya (coming)
Definition: Skillful means that meets practitioners where they are
Application: Avalokane adapts to individual readiness and spiritual development level
Divine Tara Etymology: tārā (star/guide)</description></item><item><title>Avalokane Meditation: Key Insights &amp; Quotes</title><link>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/quotes-avalokane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/quotes-avalokane/</guid><description>Key Insights &amp;amp; Quotes from Avalokane On the Nature of Avalokane &amp;ldquo;Avalokane is the practice of beholding from above — learning to perceive reality from a higher, more expansive vantage point.&amp;rdquo;
Chapter 1, page 23
&amp;ldquo;You cannot &amp;lsquo;do&amp;rsquo; avalokane the way you &amp;lsquo;do&amp;rsquo; contemplation or concentration meditation. It&amp;rsquo;s a practice that engages the higher faculty of spiritual awareness.&amp;rdquo;
Chapter 1, page 25
&amp;ldquo;Avalokane asks nothing of you but presence — no spiritual resume required for divine grace to find you.</description></item><item><title>Avalokane Meditation: Philosophical Framework</title><link>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/philosophy-avalokane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/philosophy-avalokane/</guid><description>Philosophical Framework of Avalokane Ancient Wayist Tradition Avalokane emerges from the ancient Wayist tradition, which predates Christianity by approximately 200 years. Wayism teaches that spiritual development occurs through the Butterfly Path — the natural progression from soul-mind identification to spirit-mind realization.
The practice of mystical beholding has been preserved through centuries of Wayist teaching, offering a direct method for engaging the immortal aspects of human awareness.
The Ten-Mind System Human awareness operates through ten distinct minds, organized in three primary groups:</description></item><item><title>Avalokane Meditation: The Art of Mystical Beholding</title><link>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/_index-avalokane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wayism.github.io/org/core-texts/avalokane-book/_index-avalokane/</guid><description>theWAY of Avalokane Meditation The Art of Mystical Beholding An advanced Wayist meditation practice for sincere spiritual seekers
About This Practice Avalokane is the Sanskrit term for mystical beholding — spiritual awareness that transcends ordinary thinking and allows you to perceive reality from a divine perspective through your spirit-minds rather than brain-mind.
The word itself tells the story: ava (from above) + lok (to see/behold) + ane (the art of) = the practice of beholding from above.</description></item></channel></rss>